So, let's go and practice using CloudFront
but first we have to create an S3 bucket
to hold our files for our distribution.
So, let's create a bucket
and I'll call this one demo-cloudFront-stephane-V4,
and it will scroll down, leave everything
as the default and click on Create bucket.
Okay, so my bucket is now created
and I'm going to upload some files in it.
So, let me add files and I will choose my three files,
beach, coffee, and index.html.
So, let's upload them and now they've been uploaded.
So, if I go in my bucket, we can see all of them,
and as a reminder, if I go on index.html,
I have two ways of open it.
The first one is to use the object URL, but if I try it,
I get an access denied because my object is not public.
And if I go and click on Open here,
this generates a pre-signed,
so let's allow pop-ups,
this generates a pre-signed URL for my S3 object,
which allows me to access the object,
so I see I love coffee and Hello World
but I still don't see the image
because the image itself is not public.
So, let's see how we can instead use CloudFront
to make these files accessible without making them public.
So, let's open up the CloudFront console,
and as you can see on the top right corner
it is a global service because, well,
CloudFront is a global distribution
so there's no region selection.
We next have to choose an origin domain.
So, as you can see, I get my Amazon S3 buckets,
or my elastic load balancer or whatever.
So, if I choose my buckets,
I could choose my demo CloudFront bucket,
clicking out on here.
But here you can enter really any domain name you want
including custom HTTP origins, this is fine.
So, then the origin access.
How do you access the identity?
Well, because this is Amazon S3, we have multiple ways,
we have public, which is that
the bucket itself must be public
but this is not the case for us.
Then, we have Origin access control, which is OAC.
That's the recommended way we'll be using it,
and here it was OAI, it was the previous way of doing it,
but now we're going to use the new way
called OAC, Origin access Control.
So, we need to create an origin access control.
So, to do so, let's click on Create control setting
and it just gives us a name for it.
So, this is good, and let's click on Create.
So, now this has been created and we will have
to update the S3 bucket policy.
So, that's so that CloudFront can access our S3 buckets
because if you go right now in here
and look at our bucket itself under Permissions,
and scroll down, the bucket policy is currently empty,
and so CloudFront will not be able to access it.
So, right now we'll leave it as is.
I'm going to scroll down and skip many different settings.
For WAF, we're going to just disable
the security protections because we don't need them.
And lastly, the one thing we have to do
is the default root object is index.html.
Okay, so everything looks good.
Let's create our distribution,
and our distribution can take some time to be created.
As you can see here,
the S3 bucket policy needs to be updated.
So, I can click on copy policy here,
and there is a shortcut from here
to go straight to your bucket policy settings.
So, page, so here we go, we have it.
Now, let's click on Edit,
and we're going to paste the policy we just printed.
And by the way, if you somehow lose access to this policy,
you can go under Origins, then in here in Origins,
you click on Edits, you scroll down,
and here you will find the policy statement
to copy and paste here.
So, if you look at this bucket policy now,
we allow the platform service to do get object
on any file in our bucket,
as long as the platform distribution,
So this is a condition, is the one we created.
So, this basically allows our distribution
to access S3 buckets.
This is good, this was generated by AWS.
We don't to do anything besides this.
So, the permissions are now correct.
So, back in CloudFront, let's cancel this,
and we go to our distribution,
and we have to wait until it becomes deployed.
My CloudFront distribution is now ready,
so I'm going to copy the domain name, open a new tab.
And as you can see now I get
I love Coffee, Hello World, and my image.
So, you can go to /coffee.jpeg
and of course this will work, and you can go to /beach.jpeg,
and this will work as well.
But the cool thing about it
is that now if I refresh this page,
this is served actually from the platform cache,
and not from the S3 bucket itself because,
well, I requested the file once,
so now they are automatically sent by CloudFront,
as you can see, the loading is much quicker.
And again, if I go to index.html,
this is served from the cache.
So, this is the beauty of CloudFront.
Now, we've done one request
against Amazon S3 through CloudFront
and then the rest is cached on the distribution itself.
So, if I go back now to CloudFront, on the left hand side,
just to show you, you have the origin access,
and this is where you will find your origin access controls.
And we can see that this one was created,
and is active right now,
and is assigned to this distribution.
So, okay, that's it.
We've seen how CloudFront works.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.